# **James Keary**

347-765-3499 I jkeary@gmail.com I www.jameskeary.com I Philadelphia PA, USA

## **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with wide range of technical experiences. Spent the past 4 years and 10 months coding for the Washington D.C. advocacy marketing start-up Crowdskout. Backend work was done in PHP's Laravel framework, using multiple database solutions such as MySQL, MongoDB and ElasticSearch, and other techs such as AWS, Resque queue manager with Redis DB, Jenkins task automation server, and Ansible script automation. Front end work was done in Typescript, ES6, AngularJS, and SCSS using Grunt task runner, and the NPM package manager. Local development was done on Linux OS and Vagrant Virtualbox using dev tools such as Postman, PhpStorm IDE, VSCode and Vim text editors, Filezilla, Git for code management, zshell, iterm, with Atlassian Agile organizational tools. Used test driven and fault tolerant development principles.

### **EMPLOYMENT**

**Crowdskout, Washington DC**, August 2014 - June 2019 **Feature Team Engineer**, January 2019 - June 2019

- Updated platform features from legacy code to use Typescript language and ES6 principles. **Integrations Team Engineer**, *October 2016 January 2019*
- Built and managed our integrations team: instructed 3 engineers on how to build integrations, set up dev environments, introduced them to the codebase, scoped out their projects, ticketed and assigned work loads, examined PRs and lead code reviews, and acted as a general team resource.
- Built and maintained our integrations codebase that connected Crowdskout's API to a growing suite
  of 25 or so 3rd party softwares including MailChimp, CallFire and Salesforce. Developed with
  scalability and speed in mind; uni and bidirectional syncing of client datasets ranging from a few
  thousand up to 300 million data points via 3rd party APIs and SFTP servers with flat file ingestion.

Full Stack Engineer, August 2014 - October 2016

- Developed Crowdskout platform features; including the Form Creation tool, CSV Export tool, platform Activity Tracking, and various other solo and team efforts.
- Sole engineer of <u>www.modernnotion.com</u>, a pop science and history articles website. Backend PHP Wordpress, Front end ReactJS. Built with responsive and mobile-first design strategies.
- Built Crowdskout's Wordpress Plugin, a page view and click tracker; PHP Wordpress, SVN code management.

# NYU Steinhardt, Research Programmer, Medical Imaging Sonification Project, 2013 - 2014

- As a student, I worked as a part time research assistant where I developed and designed interactive audio software and audio processing algorithms to sonify 3D datasets of Positron Emission Tomography (PET) brain scan data from the NYU Langone Medical Center.
- Developed and prepared different sonifcation methods, testing them on audio experts and doctors to understand if our methodologies aided doctors in the diagnosis of Alzheimer's dementia.
- Worked in Matlab, Csound and SuperCollider programming languages and Logic Pro DAW.
- Co-authored publications; Sonification Method To Enhance the Diagnosis of Dementia (2014) and The Triple Tone Sonification Method to Enhance the Diagnosis of Alzheimer's Dementia (2016). Gave a talk at the International Conference on Auditory Displays (ICAD) 2014 about or research.

### **EDUCATION**

New York University, Steinhardt, Masters of Music, Music Technology, 2011 - 2013, GPA 3.43 Oberlin College, Bachelor of Arts, 2002 - 2006

### **EXTRAS**

• Other programming languages I have experience with include Python, Java, C, and Pure Data.